hey guys this looks like a fun one it
wants us to solve for x and it gives us
this triangle that is not to scale we
have angle measures of a de 2 a de and a
de it gives us the base is 5 cm and it
wants us to find this longest side if
you want to try on your own pause it
right now because I'm going to solve it
in 3 2 1 so first thing we know the sum
of the interior angles of any triangle
adds to 180° so a + 2 a + a will equal
180 and on the left hand side a + 2 a +
a simplifies to 4 a and that's still
equal to 180 now to get a by itself we
can divide both sides by four 4 a ID 4
is equal to a and 180 / 4 is 45 so we
now know that a is equal to 45 and every
single time I do one of these videos
someone tells me that a is actually
equal to
45° but if you notice with the degree
symbol up here this is a degrees so if a
was 45° that would make this 45° de so
we know it's not 45°
so a is only 45 and that would make this
angle 45° I wonder if someone will still
comment that in the comments even after
I said this but a is for sure equal to
45 and then this a degrees up here will
change into 45° and this 2 a degrees
will change into 90° so we know for sure
this image is not to scale because 90°
would be perpendicular right here in
fact we can fix this and this is what it
should look like and now that we fix the
triangle let's get rid of the knot and
now this is image to scale that looks
nice now in any isos triangle that's any
triangle with two angles the same the
sides opposite those congruent angles
will be congruent since this side is 5
cm this side will also be 5 cm so right
now there's two different ways we can
solve this we can use the notes for a 45
4590 triangle and this tells us that the
hypotenuse is whatever this side is
times the < tk2 so if this side is 5 cm
the hypotenuse will be 5 < tk2 2 cm or
the other method is to do Pythagorean
theorem it's a^ 2 + b^2 is equal to c^2
so we can do 5^ 2 + 5^2 is = to x^2 on
the left hand side 5^2 is equal to 25
and 5^2 is equal to 25 and 25 + 25 is
equal to 50 and then to solve for x we
can square root both sides of the
equation the rooot 50 can be broken down
into rooot 25 * 2 and then we can give
each of these their own square root and
the square root of 25 is equal to 5 and
when taking the square < TK of x^2 since
we know this is a distance it must be
positive so this simplifies into X and
now we have X is equal to POS 5 < tk2
this is the answer to our question let's
put a box around it how exciting hey
guys I was just editing this and I
realized right at the end here I want to
point out that X does not equal 5 < tk2
cm it's 5 tk2 without the centim label
and that's because that hypotenuse would
end up being 5 < tk2 cm s I know this
one isn't as crazy as some of my other
videos but I really like the fact that
the image is not to scale and I really
like the discussion of the labels for
the variables how you don't want to make
it 45 degrees degrees so I thought this
would make a fun video I hope you guys
liked it and if you like to see more
math content I'm going to put a
subscribe button somewhere up here how
exciting